dell.ca 2014-12-13

# Privacy Statement | Dell Canada

### Canada Specific Privacy

#### Privacy Statement Regarding Customer and Online User Information ("Privacy Statement")  
Effective date: November 21, 2013

This privacy statement governs the Personal Information we collect from our customers and online from our website users ("you"), through Dell products, services, software, websites, contacts, or our relationship with you. **"Personal Information"** means information about an identifiable individual as more particularly described under applicable privacy legislation, and includes name, telephone number, and email address but generally does not include business contact information.

The Privacy Statement applies to Dell Canada Inc., Dell Financial Services Canada Limited and their respective Canadian corporate affiliates* (collectively, "Dell", "we", "us" or "our"). This Privacy Statement does not apply to our Service Providers or to any other third parties, even if their websites are linked to our website. We recommend you review the privacy statements of the other parties with whom you interact.

Please refer to your warranty statements and Dell's Return Policy for policies that apply to information contained on hard drives returned to Dell.

For the purposes of this Privacy Statement, "corporate affiliates" means any entity or joint venture that is directly or indirectly owned or controlled by Dell Inc. "Service Providers" means any subcontractor, vendor or other entity with whom we have an ongoing business relationship to provide products, services, or information.

Scope of this Privacy Statement  
Information We Collect  
How We Use Personal Information  
Disclosing Personal Information  
Your Consent to the Collection, Use and Disclosure of Your Personal Information  
How You Can Access Your Information  
For How Long and Where Does Dell Keep My Personal Information  
Selecting Your Communication Preferences  
How We Secure Your Personal Information  
Collection and Use of Children's Personal Information  
How We Use Cookies and Web Beacons  
Third-Party Websites and Services  
Changes to Our Privacy Statement Regarding Customer and Online User Information  
Contact Us

#### Scope of this Privacy Statement  

This Privacy Statement applies only to Personal Information collected from individual customers. It does not apply to corporate or business contact information. In addition, this Privacy Statement is not applicable to Personal Information that has been aggregated or made anonymous and no longer specifically relates to an identifiable individual. Dell reserves the right to use aggregated or anonymous information in any manner it considers appropriate.

#### Information We Collect  

  * We may ask you to provide Personal Information when you 
  * Use our website; 
  * Request quotes, services, support, or information; 
  * Place orders for products or services; 
  * Apply for credit, leasing or other financing products or services; 
  * Participate in surveys, sweepstakes, or other promotional activities; 
  * Subscribe to newsletters, promotional emails, or other materials; 
  * Apply for a job, submit your resume/CV, or create a candidate profile; or 
  * Contact us.

Information we may request includes your email address, name, home address, and telephone number. If you make a purchase, we may ask for your credit card number and billing information.

If you request credit, leasing, or other financing products or services, we may also ask for your Social Insurance Number (SIN) and other data (including information regarding your income, assets, debts, liabilities, your banking information, and information regarding your financial and credit history) to process your credit, leasing, or financing request as permitted by law. We will ask for your Social Insurance Number (SIN) so that we can provide your information to a consumer or credit reporting agency in order to perform a credit analysis. The SIN is the best way to ensure that the information we are provided by the reporting agency actually refers to you. Providing your SIN assists us with accurate and timely processing of your application. However, providing your SIN is optional and choosing not to provide it will not prevent you from obtaining credit or other products or services from us. When you are a credit or leasing customer, we collect information about your transactions, including your purchases, account balances and payments.

Job applicants may be requested to provide information such as educational background, employment experience, job interest information, and criminal background checks. We may also collect demographic information, such as your business or company information, age, gender, interests, preferences and favourites. Forms that you fill in may indicate whether information requested is mandatory or voluntary for the purpose for which the information is requested. 

We may collect information about your visits to our websites, including the pages you view, the links and ads you click, search terms you enter, and other actions you take in connection with the Dell websites and services. We may also collect certain information from the browser you used to come to our website, such as your Internet Protocol (IP) address, browser type and language, access times, the Uniform Resource Locator (URL) of the website that referred you to our website and to which URL you browse away from our site if you click on a link on our site.

In order to offer you a more consistent and personalized experience in your interactions with Dell, information collected through one source may be combined with information obtained through other Dell resources. We may also supplement the information we collect with information obtained from other parties. For example, Dell may collect data on which pages you visit on the website and later combine this information on purchases you complete on Dell.com. We may use the combined data to determine which ads to serve you on Dell.com or third party websites or to determine what ads to include in future emails sent to you.Click here to learn more about how we determine which ads to serve you.

Some Dell services may be co-branded and offered in conjunction with another company. If you register for or use such services, both Dell and the other company may receive information collected in conjunction with the co-branded services, and may use the information according to each company's privacy statement and other agreements with you.

#### How We Use Personal Information  

Dell uses your personal information to:

  * Deliver the services and support, or carry out, the transactions you have requested; 
  * Determine your eligibility to receive credit, leasing, or other financing products or services, including obtaining reports from consumer or credit reporting agencies, financial institutions or finance companies; 
  * Verify your identity and creditworthiness; 
  * Send communications to you, such as product safety information, your transactions status (for example, order confirmations), information about products and services available from Dell and its corporate affiliates, promotional offers, and surveys; 
  * Customize, analyze, and improve our products, services (including the content and advertisements on our website and in emails), technologies, communications and relationship with you; 
  * Identify patterns of behaviour to offer relevant suggestions to users. For example, based on non-identifiable data collected through cookies on our website, we may be able to determine that users who viewed certain products may also like other specific products. These cookies are not tied to personal identifiers; 
  * Enforce our conditions of sale, website terms and/or separate agreements (if applicable) with you; 
  * Manage, administer, collect and enforce accounts, collect debts, and process payments; 
  * Meet our legal, regulatory, insurance and processing requirements; 
  * Protect you and us from fraud, identity theft, unauthorized access to your account, and other prohibited or illegal activities; 
  * Protect the security or integrity of the website, our business, or our products or services; or 
  * Otherwise, as disclosed to you at the point of collection or as permitted or required by law.

#### Disclosing Personal Information  

We may share your Personal Information with corporate affiliates to carry out transactions you request or to make our business or that of our corporate affiliates more responsive to your needs. We may disclose your Personal Information to credit bureaus and credit reporting agencies and financial institutions and to other third parties as necessary to maintain your credit history, provide credit references, process payments, and otherwise manage our accounts and fulfill our legal and regulatory requirements.

We may also use your Personal Information and share your Personal Information among corporate affiliates and our authorized third party marketing and advertising agencies in order to communicate with you regarding products and services that may be of interest to you and to develop and implement customer programs, unless you opt out from this use.

We will not disclose your Personal Information to third parties for their own marketing purposes unless you have provided consent. 

We may disclose and/or transfer Personal Information to a third party in the event of a proposed or actual purchase, sale (including a liquidation, realization, foreclosure or repossession), lease, merger, amalgamation or any other type of acquisition, disposal, transfer, conveyance or financing of all or any portion of Dell Inc. or its corporate affiliates, or of any of the business or assets or shares of Dell Inc. or Dell Canada Inc. or their respective corporate affiliates, or divisions thereof in order for you to continue to receive products and services from the third party.

We may also disclose your Personal Information in connection with law enforcement, fraud prevention, or other legal action; as required or permitted by law or regulation; or if Dell reasonably believes it is necessary to protect Dell, its customers, or the public.

We may transfer your Personal Information to Service Providers that help Dell carry out transactions you request, that help Dell promote and market additional goods, services and special offers from us and/or our corporate affiliates, or that help Dell to customize, analyze, and/or improve our communication or relationship with you, and then only with Service Providers who share Dell's commitment to protecting your Personal Information. For example, Dell may use Service Providers to deliver email to Dell customers, may work with Service Providers to customize ads based on pages users visit on Dell.com (including Dell.ca), or may allow Service Providers to collect aggregate information to identify trends and analyze which pages are visited most often by visitors to Dell.com. Dell may disclose Personal Information to Service Providers to complete transactions or market on Dell's behalf, but those Service Providers are prohibited from using your Personal Information for their own purposes. 

Some Service Providers are located outside of Canada, including in the United States. Likewise, some Dell facilities may also be located outside of Canada. As a result, your Personal Information may be collected, processed and stored in another jurisdiction. Reasonable contractual and other measures we may take to protect your Personal Information while processed or handled by these Service Providers are subject to legal requirements applicable to our Service Providers, for example lawful requirements to disclose Personal Information to government authorities in certain circumstances. 

All such Service Providers are required to limit their use of your Personal Information for the purposes and in the manner we have instructed them. They have also committed to keeping your Personal Information confidential, using it only as directed by Dell, and to secure your Personal Information in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Statement. All Service Providers who receive information from Dell to use on Dell's behalf are obligated to manage the information under Dell's Privacy Statement. 

#### Your Consent to the Collection, Use and Disclosure of Your Personal Information  

The provision of your Personal Information to Dell means that you agree and consent that we may collect, use and disclose your Personal Information in accordance with this Privacy Statement. In addition, from time to time and where appropriate, Dell may request your specific authorization or consent for the collection, use and disclosure of your Personal Information for other purposes. 

Subject to legal and contractual restrictions, you may withdraw your consent to our further collection, use or disclosure of information at any time by giving us reasonable notice. However, where we have provided or are providing certain services or products to you, including but not limited to credit, leasing or other financing products or services, your consent will be valid so long as necessary to fulfill the purposes for which the information was collected. In addition, you may not be permitted to withdraw your consent to certain necessary collection, uses and disclosures of your Personal Information (for example but not limited to maintaining reasonable business and transaction records, and the ongoing disclosure of your Personal Information to consumer or credit reporting agencies). 

Please be aware that in certain circumstances, Dell may be required to disclose your Personal Information without your consent such as to law enforcement or other government officials. This could arise, for example, where disclosure is required: 

  * To comply with a subpoena, warrant or order made by a court with jurisdiction to compel the production of such information; 
  * To legal authorities for the detection and prevention of fraud or other criminal activity; or 
  * To our legal counsel in the event that any matter may the subject of litigation.

If Dell should be required to release your Personal Information without your consent, such as for the reasons listed above, we keep a record of what information was released, to which party it was released and why the circumstances necessitated such release. In order to respect your privacy to the fullest extent possible, Dell will only release the information to the extent that we are required to do so.

#### How You Can Access Your Information  

Dell wants to help you keep your Personal Information accurate. To view or edit your Personal Information that has been stored online in your Dell 'My Account,' please visit the My Account / Premier Account sections of the dell.com website. For the security of your account, you will be required to sign in with your login ID and password. You may also contact us at [privacy@dell.com](mailto:privacy@dell.com) to request access to or correction or update of your Personal Information. 

Dell will permit you the reasonable right of access and review of your Personal Information. We will endeavour to provide the information in question within a reasonable time and no later than 30 days following receipt of your request. If we require additional time, or if we feel that we have grounds to refuse your request, we will notify you of new timing for our reply and/or the reasons for our extension or refusal. Dell reserves the right to charge for copies of your records; however we will always let you know in advance if there is any such charge. Dell will provide information from its records in a form that is easy to understand. To protect you, Dell may require sufficient information to allow us to confirm that the person making the request is authorized to do so before granting access or making corrections.

#### For How Long and Where Does Dell Keep My Personal Information  

We keep Personal Information only so long as is needed in order to meet the purposes set out in this Policy, including for the purpose of enabling us to meet any legal or regulatory requirements. Dell has retention standards for customer information and records management which set out these timelines. We have retention policies in place that govern the destruction of Personal Information.

#### Selecting Your Communication Preferences  

You may choose to receive or not receive marketing communications from Dell by indicating your preferences. Opportunities to select your preferences include the following: 

  * The My Account / Premier Account sections on Dell.com allow you to choose whether you wish to receive marketing communications from Dell.com, and to subscribe or unsubscribe to newsletters about our products and services; and 
  * At any point you can also visit our [List Removal Page](https://ecomm.dell.com/GSC/ListRemoval/Index?returnPath=www.dell.com&c=ca&l=en) and request to be removed from our advertising and marketing lists (catalogs, telephone, faxes, and email); 
  * At the time you save a cart while shopping online, you can choose to receive email reminders; 
  * Any marketing by Dell, or any third parties on behalf of Dell, will be conducted in accordance with applicable laws.

Please allow up to 10 business days for your email preferences to take effect. 

Because some promotions, such as direct mail catalogues, are developed in advance, you may sometimes receive solicitations after we receive your preference request. 

You may withdraw your consent to Dell's collection, use and disclosure of your Personal Information at any time, subject to legal or contractual restrictions and reasonable notice, by contacting us at [privacy@dell.com](mailto:privacy@dell.com) or by opting out of cookies, as described in the About Our Ads section below. If you choose to withdraw your consent, we will inform you of the implications of withdrawing consent. Typically, this may include limitations such as no longer receiving email marketing, no longer receiving personalized advertising, inability to save account information, or no longer having access to the saved cart feature.

#### How We Secure Your Personal Information  

Dell is committed to protecting the security of your Personal Information. We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your Personal Information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure, such as encryption, passwords, physical security, etc. While we strive to protect your Personal Information, Dell cannot ensure or warrant that the Personal Information or private communications you transmit to us will always remain private, and you provide this information at your own risk. For more information about our security measures, please click here. 

If a password is used to help protect your accounts and Personal Information, it is your responsibility to keep your password confidential. Do not share this information with anyone. If you are sharing a computer with anyone you should always log out before leaving a site or service to protect access to your information from subsequent users. 

We will not ask you to transmit your SIN on the Internet unless the connection is secure or the SIN is encrypted, or require you to transmit your SIN to access a website without requiring additional authentication.

#### Collection and Use of Children's Personal Information  

Dell takes children's privacy seriously. If you are under the age of majority in the province in which you reside, then please do not submit any Personal Information through our websites without the express consent and participation of a parent or guardian.

#### How We Use Cookies and Web Beacons  

Click here for information about the use of cookies and web beacons.

#### About Our Ads

Click here for information about how we and our partners use cookies and web beacons to customize content and to tailor advertisements and email you receive, including how to decline participation in the use of ad serving on Dell.ca and how to unsubscribe from email marketing communications.

#### Third-Party Websites and Services  

Please be aware that other websites that may be accessed through our website may collect personally identifiable information about you. The information practices of those third-party websites linked to Dell.com are not covered by this privacy statement. We generally use the "" symbol to mark links that go to third party sites. Please be aware that, in providing services on Dell's behalf, our Service Providers may collect Personal Information about you. All such Service Providers who receive Personal Information on behalf of Dell are required to use this information for the purposes and in the manner Dell has instructed them.

#### Changes to Our Privacy Statement Regarding Customer and Online User Information  

We will occasionally update this Privacy Statement. If we make changes to the Privacy Statement or make any material changes to how Dell will use your Personal Information, we will revise the Privacy Statement to reflect such changes and revise this Privacy Statement effective date, included at the end of this section. We encourage you to periodically review this statement to be informed of how Dell is protecting your Personal Information.

#### Contact Us  

If you would like to contact us for any reason regarding our privacy practices, including for information regarding our policies and procedures with respect to Service Providers outside of Canada, you may write to us or email us at the following addresses: 

Dell Canada Privacy Department.   
155 Gordon Baker Road, Suite 501   
Toronto, Ontario M2H 3N5   
Email: [privacy@dell.com](mailto:privacy@dell.com). 

*As of the Effective Date of this Statement, Dell's Canadian corporate affiliates include Dell Canada Inc., Dell Software Canada Inc., and Dell Financial Services Canada Limited.
